In our next paragraph, about 30 little turtles, we deal with another aspect of L,
namely consonant clusters. When you have a D-L combination, you need to apply what
you learned about liaisons and the American T as well as the L. Since the two
sounds are located in a similar position in the mouth, you know that they're going
to be connected, right? You also know that all of these middle T's are going to be
pronounced D, and that you're going to leave the tongue stuck to the top of your
mouth. That may leave you wondering, where is the air to escape? The L sound is what
determines that. For the D, you hold the air in, the same as for a final D. Then
for the L, you release it around the sides of the tongue. Let's go through the steps
before proceeding to our next exercise.